Justin Pullman

Email: jpullman@iastate.edu Phone: (309) 414-7043 Website: jpullman.com

SUMMARY Highly motivated soon to be new graduate with over 5 years of experience in team-based product design and fabrication. Demonstrated leadership skills in both small and large team group projects. Continuous learner having a multidisciplinary background with expertise in CAD, programming, and microprocessors. Consistently recognized as a top performer with a strong work ethic, and consistently achieving exceptional results in all projects.

EDUCATION

Iowa State University, Ames IA,

- Bachelor of Science in Aerospace Engineering
- GPA: 3.27 / 4.00

EXPERIENCE

Robotics Coach — Peoria Academy, Peoria, IL,

August 2019 - December 2019

Anticipated Grad: December 2023

- Instructed students in various engineering disciplines to teach the design process and fostered communication through hands-on activities.
- Motivated problem-solving by recognizing and rewarding innovative thinking to garner successful contribution from students.
- Encouraged critical thinking by posing open-ended questions.

Mechatronics Technical Internship Experience—Caterpillar, Peoria, IL, June 2018 - August 2018

- Assisted in debugging engine control modules using custom software.
- Utilized MATLAB and Simulink to perform hardware in the loop test configurations.
- Gained insight into engine model development by collaborating with industry engineers.
- Demonstrated attention to detail by compiling GPS data from diverse sources and formats.

LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES

Design Team Leader — Senior Design Project, Ames, IA,

January 2023 - Present

- Led a 4-person team in the iterative design of 2 small unmanned aerial vehicles.
- Distilled final product features and trade studies into technical level documentation.
- Demonstrated attention to detail through identifying potential complications.
- Presented technical material to potential clients.

Founding member — Autonomous Robotics Club (ARC), Ames, IA, August 2022 - Present

- Designed a robot using CAD to compete in the Intelligent Ground Vehicle Competition.
- Developed a virtual robot using Gazebo and ROS2 (Robot Operating System).
- Conducted design reviews and planned task breakdowns.

Mechanical Lead, Team Leader — FIRST Robotics Team, Peoria, IL, August 2015 - May 2019

- Led the design and fabrication of a new 3D printable drive system.
- Led a 30-person team in the design and fabrication of a 150 lb. robot including system test, automation, and robotics field applications.
- Facilitated effective communication between departments.
- Headed up product management, keeping the team on task and on track.

SKILLS

- CAD Software: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk AutoCAD, Creo, and Ansys
- Programming languages: Python, MATLAB, C, C++
- Proficient with Arduino, Raspberry Pi, and Linux.
- Passion for Robotics, Geographic flexibility, Rapid learner, Strong problem-solving skills.